Look, Tsubomi-chan.
When you make frogs float,
they start swimming.
Wow, how cute.
I can make the bar all squishy.
You're amazing, Mob-kun.
That's the evening chime. Let's go home.
That was so much fun!
Oh... it was just a dream.
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
I realized that my youth was grey
The root of this irritation is unknown
My brain runs parallel with this emotional train
Struggling adolescence
Don't disturb the subconscious mind
Who's that behind me?
Opposing ideas, distortion
Purge the sorrow
So, do what you can now.
My life
Finally
Break it down!!
(WANT) desire (YOUNG) and sincerity
(BURN) they begin to sprout (1) within my chest
(TRANCE) I won't awaken (CHANCE) but I want to
(STANCE) both sides of the coin
(1) are back-to-back
Accept me as I am
Conflicting freedom and relations
If they can become one
That smile will be
One and only "1"
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
"Mob Psycho 100 III"
MOB MOB WOW!
One and only "1"
"Mob Psycho 100 III"
"Mob Psycho 100 "
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
One and only "1"
"Mob 1
- Moving~"
--Happy New Year!
--Did you go somewhere during break?
My grandma's place.
Did you finish it?
Yeah, I did.
Happy New Year.
We start the third term today.
"Hope" "Future" "Future Prospects” Happy
New Year. We start the third term today.
"Hope" "Future" "Future Prospects”
"Hope" "Future" "Future Prospects” I'll be collecting your
homework from winter break after the opening assembly today.
I'll be collecting your homework from winter
break after the opening assembly today.
"Basic Middle School English Drills” "Middle School Math 2" I'll be
collecting your homework from winter break after the opening assembly today.
I'll be collecting your homework from winter
break after the opening assembly today.
You all need to get over
the winter-break slump
and start studying for
your entrance exams.
"Opening Assembly" and start
studying for your entrance exams.
"Opening Assembly"
"Opening Assembly" Make sure you all work
hard together while you're still classmates.
"Opening Assembly"
Oh, the class shuffles.
Maybe when I become a third-year,
I'll be in the same class as Tsubomi-chan.
Oh, I have one more announcement to make.
Takane Tsubomi-san from Class 3
will be moving next month.
What?
Huh? Moving...?
Wait, what?
This is so sudden that
my head can't keep up.
What? I mean, I was planning to tell her how
I feel after entrance exam season was over.
But... I mean... I was still
supposed to have another year...
No, really, wait...
I haven't... I haven't even
gotten to do anything yet.
Nothing's... happened.
I need to... ask her out.
What's the matter, Kageyama?
Did you forget your homework?
Uh, no...
Oh, right...
Mob feels a certain way about Takane-san.
But...
"I need to ask her out..." "I
need to ask her out..." But...
"I need to ask her out..."
"I need to ask her out..." "I need to ask her out..."
-1 need to ask her out. -1 need to ask her out.
--I need to ask her out.
She's the top idol at this school.
How are you gonna take on
all of these rivals, Mob?
"Body Improvement Club"
A-Ask her out?!
Yes...
Are you sane, Kageyama?!
So...
...I was hoping you could
tell me your experiences,
or how to make sure I don't upset her...
Advice like that!
Experiences?
Kageyama!
You're the shadow leader at Salt Middle!
Grow a pair! Show her what
White T Poison's made of!
Sorry?
Er, just... You know...
Show her White T Poison's... uh, made of...
Kageyama... Take off your clothes.
Huh? Okay.
Ow...
You're developing some
excellent muscles there!
The experience you're looking for
has accumulated in those!
We're seeing the fruits of your labor!
I'm sure that the person you
have in mind will tell you...
...that your muscles are worthy!
Thank you! Very much!
Let us also strive for
new heights and train!
Yeah!
Body Improvement!
Fight on! Fight on! Fight on! Fight on!
Um...
Could I get some advice
on asking her out?
I'd really appreciate it...
Um...
Like the Telepathy Club could actually give
you advice about asking someone out.
--Oh, good point.
--Uh, hello?!
But, man, I can't believe
Takane-san is moving.
I've had a crush on her for a while.
Maybe I'll try asking her out, too.
Takenaka-kun, are you planning
on reading Tsubomi-chan's mind?
That would never work for too long,
and I don't plan on taking out my earplugs.
But if you read a girl's mind,
you could be super popular,
according to Tome-san.
What the heck would President Kurata
know about how a girl feels?
Okay, that's enough, you two!
You sure were running your mouths
while I was frozen
trying to figure out
what the heck's going on.
You're asking her out?
Mob-kun, are you seriously
serious about it this time?
--Yes.
--I see.
All right, then.
I'll give you a piece of very good advice.
You should definitely
change up your hairstyle!
I'll keep the rest of what
I want to say to myself!
Sorry, we can't really offer advice,
so we'll just support you from afar.
I wish you the best.
You've got this, Kageyama-senpai!
U-Um, Tsubomi-chan...
I wanted to talk to you about
something. Is that okay?
I-I wuv you...
I wuv you, Tsubomi-chan.
Please go out with me!
--I'm sorry.
--B-But why?
Oh, do I really need
to tell you the reason?
I mean, I have absolutely
no interest in you...
S-Sorry!
Jeez... There's still that many?
I don't even know most of these people.
What a pain.
What are you doing, Mob-kun?
Takane-san's not in class anymore.
Oh! Did she go home already?!
I see... She went home...
Then, I guess I'll just
have to give up for today.
Oh, well. I'll just
have to try another day...
"Sliiiiiiiiiiide"
She's behind the school.
Behind the school?
What's she doing there?
While you've been wasting your time here,
all the other boys have
been asking her out.
Say what now?
I-I-1 better go...
"Tup Tup Tup Tup Tup"
"Tup Tup Tup Tup Tup" If you go
right now, she's gonna reject you!
If you go right now,
she's gonna reject you!
It's like some weird factory assembly line
that's producing a bunch of broken-hearted lads.
You'll just get caught up in all that,
and she'll say no to you, too.
Mezato-san...
Do you think I should cut my hair?
Huh? Wait, why your hair?
What kind of guys do girls like?
He's starting to consider
more than just "work out"!
First, you need to be a gentleman.
You should always mind your manners
around all of your girl classmates.
Also, you need to be considerate.
You need to be dependable,
lend an ear to her problems,
and make her think she can
talk about anything.
If you can be that accepting,
you might just be able
to handle Takane-san as well.
I'd be able to handle her?
Yeah.
It seems as though most of the guys
just like her because of her appearance,
but I'm pretty sure
she's hiding how she really feels.
It'll be up to you to be able
to handle who she really is.
Though I honestly don't know what
the big fuss is over Takane-san.
Huh?
I mean, she doesn't seem
to trust anyone at all.
I'm pretty sure she has
no interest in other people.
How do you know that?
You can tell just by seeing
how she acts every day.
Actually, how can you not tell?
You should learn to view other people
from a different angle every now and then.
Say, Mob-kun...
What exactly do you like about her?
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office"
So... you couldn't respond to that question,
you couldn't go behind the school,
and you can't fully concentrate on work.
Come on, now, Mob-kun.
Don't go bringing this
puppy love nonsense to work.
Of course middle schoolers
fall in love just by appearances.
I understand why you want
to believe you're different,
but in the end, men are simple creatures.
Am I right, Serizawa?
Er, I didn't go to school, so I'm not sure.
You must've at least had a girl you liked.
No... I can't say that there was.
Not even one?
Come on, don't be bashful at your age.
No, wait. Are you actually serious?
I'm honestly envious that
you have someone you like.
If your feelings for her don't change,
despite what anyone says...
...that means your feelings are true, right?
Then I don't think you have
to put your reasoning into words.
Yes, exactly! That's exactly
what I was trying to say!
What's important is not what
you like about her,
it's if you truly like her or not!
If you're nervous about this,
then tell us how you really feel.
We'll hear you out.
The reason that Tsubomi-chan
caught my attention so much...
Mob-kun! Let's make a tunnel!
Sure.
Look! I'm only showing you, Tsubomi-chan!
I'm bored of that.
I'm not really sure myself.
But I know that I like her.
I've always liked Tsubomi-chan.
Then there's nothing to worry about.
Go for broke.
But I'm not sure what to say when
I ask her out. What should I do?
Well... you know...
First, you wanna be fresh and clean.
Then, remember to be sincere and faithful.
And don't forget to be fashionable
and a good listener.
Also...
Make sure to smile and don't be glum. And...
Oh, right. Setting the mood
to excite her is also important.
"The Manual to Asking Someone Out Be fresh and clean!! Always be
sincere and faithful!! Listen to them!! Smile and set the mood!!"
"The Manual to Asking Someone Out Be fresh and clean!! Always be sincere and
faithful!! Listen to them!! Smile and set the mood!!" What?! He's cheating?!
"The Manual to Asking Someone Out Be fresh and clean!! Always be
sincere and faithful!! Listen to them!! Smile and set the mood!!"
And there you have it!
I guess Reigen-san doesn't know, either.
"The Manual to Asking Someone Out Be fresh and clean!! Always be
sincere and faithful!! Listen to them!! Smile and set the mood!!"
"The Manual to Asking Someone Out Be fresh and clean!! Always be sincere and faithful!!
Listen to them!! Smile and set the mood!!" But in the end... don't worry about strategy.
But in the end...
don't worry about strategy.
There's no point in trying
to keep up appearances
with a person you want
a deep relationship with.
Just be yourself. Show her your true self.
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office"
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office" I'm sure the last thing
Tsubomi-chan wants to hear is you asking her out using my words.
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office"
Just put what you're feeling into words.
Thank you very much.
Yes, you're right. I'll do just that.
Reigen-san, I'm actually a bit surprised
you gave him that advice.
If this were me,
I'd probably try to be slick.
I mean, if they found out who I really was,
I'd get rejected in an instant.
I guess even Reigen-san is
pessimistic about these matters.
He seems really popular with our clients
who are older ladies, though...
However...
...Mob is different.
He should follow the straight and narrow.
He shouldn't bother with lies.
You've got this, Mob.
What's with all the sighing, friend?
Are you in trouble again?
Hanazawa-kun.
Huh. So your childhood
friend is transferring.
Yeah. I haven't had the chance to
actually talk to her these past few years,
and this was really sudden.
So that's why you're in
a hurry to ask her out.
Yeah.
But this is my first time,
so it's been pretty difficult.
It's really not something
to be that scared of.
It must be nice being you,
Hanazawa-kun, since you're popular.
You're nothing like me.
What are you talking about?
You're the one who said we
were alike in the first place.
Go on. Relax those shoulders.
Smile and stand proud.
You need to be more confident!
It's not like you're doing anything bad.
Are you thinking about
getting something for her?
That thought hadn't even crossed my mind.
I see... A gift, huh?
I'm usually the one getting asked out,
but when I get letters or homemade cookies,
it does make me pretty happy.
I figured that might be an option.
Homemade...
That's not gonna work.
I only know how to make rice balls.
Hey, you don't need to push yourself.
There's no guarantee that
it's better to give her something.
Actually, in your case, maybe you can get
her some flowers, even if it's a bit cliché.
I'm sure it couldn't hurt.
Flowers...
Also, I'll gladly pick out
your clothes for you.
I-I don't actually have enough money
to buy any clothes, so I'll pass this time.
Thanks, though.
Nii-san. About Takane-san moving...
Oh, you already know, Ritsu?
I see.
So you're also going to
ask her out, after all.
The time's finally arrived.
I'm honestly really nervous
just thinking about it.
How is she going to respond?
I'm pretty sure I remember Takane-san
saying she likes someone...
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office" I'm pretty
sure I remember Takane-san saying she likes someone...
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office"
Yes. The person I like is someone from
another school I met at cram school.
From what you've told me, the other person
is obviously interested in you as well.
If you ask them out, there's a very
good possibility they'll say yes.
It's over...
Anyway, I hope she doesn't
turn him down too harshly.
Ritsu...
He's probably more worried
about me than I am.
I'm not sure why, but it
somehow calms me down.
Thanks, Ritsu.
I'll give it everything I've got.
Nii-san...
Don't lose heart too much, okay?
"Every Morning Milk"
"Enjoy a glass a day!!"
"Phone Numbers"
"Takashio Takayama
Takane Tanaka"
H-Hello?
I-It's been a while, ma'am.
It's me, Shigeo.
Is Tsubomi-chan available?
Y-Yes. Thank you very much.
H-Hello, Tsubomi-chan?
S-Sorry to call you out of the blue.
I only know your house phone.
So, uh, I heard...
Um... Like...
...that you're moving away.
Oh... So it's true.
Right, of course.
Yeah, so, hey... There's something
I wanted to talk to you about.
Huh? It's a bit awkward
to say on the phone.
I was wondering if you had
some time after school tomorrow...
No, it's better if we meet
somewhere other than school.
Since we live so close to each other,
why don't we just go to the park?
Yeah. The one we used
to play at all the time.
Hm? I'm acting weird?
Really? My voice? No, it's not shaky...
Yeah... You're totally imagining it.
Yeah, uh-huh.
Yeah, that's fine.
Sure.
What? You made plans with her? Way to go!
And instead of behind the school,
you chose a nostalgic park for
the both of you. Chef's kiss.
I didn't know you had it in you, man!
If you end up going out with her,
introduce me to one of
Takane-san's girl friends.
--Sure.
--Heck yeah!
Now, then...
The point where line A
and line B intersect is -2.
--I wonder what it is...
--This will be on the test.
Despite knowing I'm going to have a really
important conversation with Tsubomi-chan,
I'm surprisingly calm.
Come to think of it,
I wonder why I thought to ask everyone
for advice about asking her out.
I think lately...
...I'm not holding in
my feelings as much.
"Seasoning Realty"
"Smiley Flowers"
I'd like an assorted bouquet... please.
Sure. Do you need a bag?
Does this work for you?
Yes.
I guess they're really small at 1,000 yen.
It's not about size anyway.
Thank you very much!
Kageyama Shigeo.
Um, you're...
Trade me.
Huh?!
"Seasoning Realty"
Are you sure? But why...?
Yeah, just come on.
Everyone...
Thank you.
There was a blue light shining
I'm wide awake this 1:30 AM
What remained even after I swiped
Are the smiles of my friends right beside me
Yes, I want someone to understand...
This wish that's hidden colorless and invisible
The breath I was holding deep within my heart
I let it all out at once and return to my senses
On days that I'm feeling apathetic
it suddenly comes to mind
These seasons I spent as if they were a given
Even if reality becomes sullied
Only the sky we saw together is real
This is more incomprehensible
Than the grammar on the blackboard
If it's going to disappear within 24 hours
This flowing story is just too lonely
I just can't do it
Just like that back hip circle I gave up on
But I'm not going to...
Give up
My present anymore
I adorn my overflowing emotions
And run through my worries and hesitations
It can't be decided from 0 to 100
Draw the incomplete future with this hand
We can't even prove its existence
But as the world stabs the middle of my chest
It overflows with cobalt blue
English Translator: Michelle Tymon Translation Editor:
Zachary Carlysle Translation Checker: Sriram Gurunathan
Kageyama-kun, I know that you're
trying to accept your powers.
You've worked so hard.
And that's why you shouldn't go any further.
Turn back now.
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 Il Episode 10:
"Mob 2 ~Rival~" Next time on
Mob Psycho 1700 Ill Episode 10:
"Mob 2
~Rival~"
"Mob 2 ~Rival~" "Mob 2 ~Rival~."